# Curtis Bowser

bwsrcurtis@gmail.com ❖ (443) 799-1122 ❖ Portfolio ❖ LinkedIn

## ABOUT ME

After graduating, I didn't know what direction to head. After working several gig jobs and contract work, I found the field of data analytics. Since then, I have committed everything I have to learning the tools needed to break into the field through courses and personal projects. I have experience working with data in Excel, querying with SQL, visualizing in Tableau, and have taken a particular interest in Python libraries such as Pandas, NumPy, MatplotLib, and Seaborn.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Google

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate

Towson University

Bachelor's of Science, Economics, GPA: 3.0

Anne Arundel Community College

Associate's of Arts, Economics

#### **SKILLS**

Programming Skills: Python(Django/Flask), MYSQL, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap

General: Data analysis, data visualization, data cleaning

## **PROJECTS**

### Tableau

Total Natural Disasters by Country since 1970

Tableau Dashboard

Utilized Tableau and Excel to manipulate data and display it in an informative way to give insights

## **Python**

Twitch

Streamer

Banner Hallmark

Exploratory Data Analysis in Python: Top 50 Spotify Songs

Kaggle Notebook

- Used raw data from Spotify's most popular songs to determine what influenced popularity
- Visualized data in Python using the Seaborn and matplotlib libraries after manipulating it with the NumPy and loading it with the Pandas libraries

Sentiment Predictor Using Machine Learning on Hotel Review Data

Kaggle Notebook

Cleaned raw text review data for machine learning, split data into test and training sets, and built Random Forest Classifier which evaluated to 74% accuracy.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

DoorDash Dec. 2020 – Present

Driver

Glen Burnie, MD

Aug. 2019 – Dec. 2020

Delivered great customer satisfaction with a 5-star rating and zero complaints over my tenure

Glen Burnie, MD

Grew a community from zero to 150 followers by increasing awareness through social media and networking

Used viewer data to plan future relevant content

Shift Supervisor/Customer Service Representative

May 2015 – Dec. 2016 Annapolis, MD

- Supervised five employees while addressing concerns and reaching daily goals responsibility
- Developed training material to more efficiently onboard new hires